{"tossups": [{"question": "In 1858, this object was recast in Whitechapel, after which a team spent 18 hours hauling this object to its belfry. This object was silenced following the death of Margaret Thatcher, and is currently disconnected during renovations of Elizabeth Tower. \u201cQuarter bells\u201d that play the Westminster Chimes every 15 minutes accompany, for ten points, what massive bell that names an iconic London clock tower?", "answer": "<b> Big Ben</b> (accept descriptive answers about the<b> bell in Big Ben</b> that say \u201cBig Ben;\u201d prompt on descriptive answers like \u201cthe bell in Westminster\u201d that don\u2019t say \u201cBig Ben;\u201d prompt on the Great Bell)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Misc Arts"}, {"question": "Hermogenes recounts this man\u2019s desire to die relatively young in order to escape the afflictions of old age in an account of this man\u2019s<em> Apology</em> by Xenophon. This husband of Xanthippe was put to death by an Athenian tribunal by drinking hemlock on charges of corrupting the youth. For ten points, name this classical philosopher whose namesake \u201cmethod\u201d employs rigorous questioning and who mentored Plato.", "answer": "<b> Socrates</b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "This case was briefly interrupted when judge Robert Jackson suffered a heart attack. The \u201cmassive resistance\u201d movement attempted to circumvent this case\u2019s ruling, which was to be carried out with \u201call deliberate speed.\u201d Thurgood Marshall argued for the plaintiffs in this case, which struck down<em> Plessy</em> <em>vs. Ferguson</em>. For ten points, name this Supreme Court case that overturned the \u201cseparate but equal\u201dprinciple in public schools.", "answer": "<b> Brown</b> vs Board of Education of Topeka, Kansas", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "During this battle, heavy fighting took place near Papelotte and La Haye Sainte. Michel Ney led a failed cavalry charge against the British during this battle, where the British Foot guards repelled an attack by the French Imperial Guard, their first defeat. The arrival of the Prussian army under Blucher swung the tide in, for ten points, what 1815 victory for the Duke of Wellington, the last major battle of the Napoleonic Wars?", "answer": "Battle of<b> Waterloo</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This man stuck a needle in his own eye during his studies on light and color, which he published in <em>Opticks</em>. This man feuded with Gottfried Leibniz over credit for the invention of calculus, a system of math that inspired, but was not proven in, this man\u2019s<em> Principia Mathematica</em>. For ten points, name this English scientist who developed the law of universal gravitation and the three laws of motion.", "answer": "Sir Isaac<b> Newton</b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {}, {"question": "This god\u2019s \u201cHorkios\u201d aspect represented his role as the keeper of oaths; guilty liars would be forced to create votive statues at this god\u2019s sanctuary at Olympia. The ancient Olympic Games were held to commemorate this deity. A gold-and-ivory sculpture of this deity was one of the original Seven Wonders of the World and was sculpted by Phidias. The eagle and bull represented, for ten points, what husband of Hera and Greek god of thunder?", "answer": "<b> Zeus</b>", "metadata": "Mythology - Mythology"}, {"question": "Members of this class began the Rokugo rebellion after the defeat of their lord. These people, who received stipends in units of rice called<em> koku</em>, first rose to prominence during the Kamakura shogunate. Members of this class who were no longer employed were known as<em> ronin</em>. These warriors had the right to bear katanas and followed the<em> bushido</em> code of honor. For ten points, name this noble military class in medieval Japan.", "answer": "<b> samurai</b> (accept<b> ronin</b> before it is mentioned; accept<b> bushi</b> before \u201cbushido\u201d is read)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "A depiction of this event dubbed a customs office as \u201cButcher\u2019s Hall;\u201d Henry Pelham created that engraving. During this event, Richard Palmes attacked Thomas Preston with a club, prompting a volley of gunfire that killed Crispus Attucks. John Adams controversially agreed to defend a group of British soldiers accused of murder for their roles in this event. For ten points, name this 1770 killing of five protesters in Massachusetts.", "answer": "<b> Boston Massacre</b> (accept the<b> Incident on King Street</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This non-African leader made the mistake of sending troops to aid Agostinho Neto of the MPLA in the Angolan Civil War, a costly intervention dubbed his country\u2019s \u201cVietnam.\u201d Though he was arrested for launching an unsuccessful raid on Moncada Barracks in a failed revolution, his later movement of 26th July was able to overthrow Fulgencio Batista with the aid of Che Guevara. For ten points, name this former Communist president of Cuba who died in 2016.", "answer": "Fidel<b> Castro</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "Near this battle\u2019s end, a storm prevented the losing side from evacuating to Gloucester Point. News of this battle prompted Lord North to proclaim, \u201cOh God, it\u2019s all over.\u201d This battle began when the Continental Army and Comte de Rochambeau\u2019s forces besieged the namesake city. For ten points, name this 1781 battle that forced Charles Cornwallis to surrender to George Washington, effectively ending the American Revolution.", "answer": "Battle of<b> Yorktown</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This city\u2019s Ford Center, as well as a facility in Baton Rouge, hosted New Orleans Hornets games in the aftermath of Hurricane Katrina. In 2008, a businessman from this city named Clay Bennett was sued by Howard Schultz for lying during the sale of the Seattle SuperSonics that he wouldn\u2019t move the Sonics to this city. For ten points, name this city where Russell Westbrook leads the NBA\u2019s Thunder.", "answer": "<b> Oklahoma City</b> (or<b> OKC</b>)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "The investigation into this event produced the Kean-Hamilton Report. Richard Drew\u2019s photograph <em>The Falling Man</em> was taken during this event. Zacarias Moussaoui is sometimes considered the twentieth perpetrator of this event, joining a group led by Mohammed Atta. Al-Qaeda orchestrated, for ten points, what 2001 terrorist attack that destroyed the World Trade Center\u2019s Twin Towers?", "answer": "<b> September 11th</b> attacks (or<b> 9/11</b>; accept the<b> 2001 World Trade Center attack</b> before\u201cWorld Trade Center\u201d is read; prompt on \u201cWorld Trade Center attack\u201d before WTC is read)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "In this region, a politician from the localist \u201cYoungspiration\u201d party used the derogatory term \u201cjee-na\u201dduring her swearing in. This region\u2019s Demosisto party suffered a setback when activist Joshua Wong was sentenced to prison. This region\u2019s districts of Mong Kok and Admiralty hosted protests as part of the 2014 Umbrella Revolution. Several Causeway Bay booksellers have been kidnapped by Chinese special agents in, for ten points, what special administrative region that was once a British colony?", "answer": "<b> Hong Kong</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "During this event, a man declared \u201cfortune favors the brave\u201d while hoping to save his friends, Rectina and Pomponianus at Stabiae. Prior to this event, an observer in Misenum noted an unusually dense and rapidly rising cloud. Letters describing this event were written to Tacitus by Pliny the Younger, whose uncle died in it. For ten points, name this 79 AD natural disaster that covered the towns of Herculaneum and Pompeii in ash.", "answer": "<b> eruption</b> of Mount<b> Vesuvius</b> (prompt on \u201cdestruction of Pompeii\u201d or \u201cdestruction of Herculaneum\u201d before mentioned; prompt on partial answers, such as \u201ca volcanic eruption\u201d)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>A structure in this city was built with two different shades of white marble and had its construction halted for twenty-five years. That monument stands at the center of a park</b> <b>planned by Pierre (+)</b> <b>L\u2019Enfant, who laid out this city. Maya Lin designed a memorial in</b> <b>this city that consists of a sloping (*)</b> wall of black marble covered in the names of soldiers. For ten points, name this city home to the Vietnam Veterans\u2019 Memorial wall and several Smithsonian museums in the National Mall.", "answer": "<b> Washington</b>, D.C. (accept<b> DC</b>; accept the<b> District of Columbia</b>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Architecture"}, {"question": "<b>This president criticized Senators Joseph Martin, Bruce Barton and Hamilton Fish for</b> <b>their conservative stances on military buildup. Owen Roberts\u2019 \u201cswitch (+)</b> <b>in time that</b> <b>saved nine\u201d prevented this man from expanding the Supreme Court to 15 justices. During this man\u2019s presidency, Congress passed the (*)</b> Social Security Act as his \u201cFireside Chats\u201d calmed America in the Great Depression. For ten points, name this president who enacted the New Deal and led the US in World War II.", "answer": "<b> F</b>ranklin Delano<b> Roosevelt</b> (or<b> FDR</b>; prompt on \u201cRoosevelt\u201d alone)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>Sergeant Leon Weckstein claimed to have spared this building from destruction during World War II. This building, located in the Square of Miracles, is thought to have been constructed by Diotisalvi. (+) Mussolini ordered the drilling of 100 holes into this structure as an attempt at fixing it. According to legend, this building was used to disprove an (*) </b>Aristotelian theory about spheres of different masses. For ten points, name this Italian structure whose weak foundation gives it a famous four-degree tilt.", "answer": "Leaning<b> Tower of Pisa</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>In one of this man\u2019s studies, he correctly predicted that misplaced envelopes addressed to groups like \u201cFriends of the Nazi Party\u201d would be \u201crescued\u201d less frequently than personal</b> <b>letters. The 1961 trial and testimony of Adolf (+)</b> <b>Eichmann in Jerusalem inspired this</b> <b>man\u2019s experiment in which the command \u201cyou must go on\u201d led over one-third of this man\u2019s subjects to administer supposedly (*) </b> lethal doses of electricity to test subjects. For ten points, name this American psychologist of a controversial obedience experiment.", "answer": "Stanley<b> Milgram</b>", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Psychology"}, {}, {"question": "<b>The Chain of Rocks Bridge spanning this river contains a 22-degree turn in its middle section. After a bridge over this river was rammed and set on fire by the</b><em><b> Effie Afton</b></em><b> in 1856, Abraham (+) Lincoln defended the bridge company in court. The city of St. Anthony was joined with Minneapolis in order to make full use of this river\u2019s resources in 1872. Mark (*)</b> Twain developed his pen name while serving as a riverboat pilot on, for ten points, what river that flows through New Orleans to the Gulf of Mexico?", "answer": "<b> Mississippi</b> River", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}